MELONY ERIN FRANCHINI Backend Software Engineer

Buena Vista, CO • melony.franchini@gmail.com • +1.303.495.4624 • LinkedIn • GitHub

SUMMARY

Backend software engineer with an M.Ed. in Adult Learning and 7+ years as a professional educator. I bring a keen ability to learn new subject matter, break down complex concepts, and effectively communicate to diverse groups of people. My enthusiasm knows no bounds when tackling any level of complexity you throw my way!

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Technology: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, ActiveRecord, SQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite3, Tailwind, AWS EC2
- Testing: Test-Driven Development (TDD), RSpec, CircleCI, Github Actions, Postman
- Others: Agile Processes, Git, GitHub, GitHub Projects, Heroku, Vultr, SendGrid, Figma, Miro, HTML, CSS
- Exploring: Amazon Web Services (AWS), Docker, Kubernetes, Redis, Sidekiq, React

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

ALPs (Advanced Language Practices), E2E Development Team | 80 hours | <u>BE Repo</u> & <u>FE Repo</u> Tech Stack: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL & SQLite3, RSpec, GitHub, Postman, Github Actions, Heroku & AWS EC2 Created a web application to query AI with user input and return foreign language corrections.

- Wrote and refined OpenAl prompt query to return consistent and reliable responses.
- Took on additional responsibilities that played a critical role in the successful delivery of the project.
- Researched 20+ hours: AWS Elastic Beanstalk deployment, EC2 instances, and DRS databases.

Do Good, Team Project | 100 Hours | <u>BE Repo</u> & <u>FE Repo</u>

Tech Stack: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, AWS S3 Bucket, Google Cloud, Twilio, Tailwind, CircleCI, Heroku Developed and deployed a web application using Service-Oriented Architecture & CRUD functionality.

- Initiated creation of a JSON contract to guarantee delivery of minimum viable product within tight deadline.
- Authenticated users with Google OAuth & rendered their Google Calendar with Google Cloud.
- Optimized database storage by storing and retrieving image metadata via an Amazon AWS S3 bucket.

Mentoring Side Projects: Phoenix Mythical Creature (Ruby) | Potluck (Ruby) | Zoo Manager (MCV) Led workshops & mentoring sessions to reinforce fundamental skills with incoming cohorts of Turing students.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Apprentice: Backend Engineer Turing School of Software & Design Remote	11/2022 – 06/2023	
 Nearing the end of an ACCET-accredited, Ruby on Rails engineering program; completion set for mid-June. 		
Founder & Language Editor English Stage lab Remote & Turkey	06/2020 – 09/2023	
 Edited medical research and other professional papers that had been translated from the 	e Turkish language.	
 University Lecturer KEPCO International Nuclear Graduate School South Korea Established school's first writing curriculum: Academic Writing, Thesis Writing, and Tech 	03/2016 – 03/2018 inical Presentations.	
 English Language Instructor Korea Hydro & Nuclear Power Co. South Korea Developed a professional English training program to improve teaching skills of senior n 	02/2014 - 03/2016 uclear engineers.	

EDUCATION

Turing School of Software and Design Certificate of Completion	06/2023
University of British Columbia Master of Education (M.Ed.) in Adult Learning and Global Change	05/2018
University of Nevada, Las Vegas Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) in Theatre Arts	08/2006

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Graduate Certificate Turkish Language (C1/Advanced)	10/2018 - 10/2020
Competent Leader & Competent Speaker Toastmasters International	03/2014 - 02/2017
K-12 Professional Educator License (Florida) English for Speakers of Other Languages	09/2013 - 05/2014
University of Colorado, Denver Graduate Certificate in Business & Entrepreneurship	09/2010 - 12/2012